A few weeks ago, a well-meaning professor tried to explain the physiological process behind viruses and the human body in a tweet and was immediately criticized for a mistake in his information.
几周前，一位教授出于好意，试图在一条推文中解释病毒作用于人体的生理过程，随即因所给信息中有一处错误而遭到批评。
He then issued an apology and deleted his erroneous tweet.
随后，他发表了致歉声明，并删除了那条有误的推文。
Communicating science beyond the academic bubble is necessary to augmenting public understanding of health and environmental issues and helping individuals make well-informed personal decisions.
要增进公众对健康和环境问题的理解，帮助个人在充分知情的情况下做出自己的决定，就必须在学术圈子之外传播科学。
However, scientists who engage in science communication must acknowledge that even in their area, their expertise is deep but narrow.
然而，从事科学传播的科学家必须承认，即便在自己的领域里，他们的专业知识虽然精深，但覆盖面也很窄。
They need to recognize the constraints in their own knowledge.
他们需要认识到自身知识的局限。
That is not to suggest that they only write or present on their own research, but rather, that they consult with an expert if the topic is outside of their discipline.
这并不是说他们只应就自己的研究撰文或作报告，而是说，如果话题超出了自己的学科范围，他们应当向专家请教。
Fact-checking with a scientist who works in the specialty will prevent the unintentional spread of misinformation, and the process of doing so may yield tiny pieces of interesting new information that can be incorporated.
向从事该专业的科学家核实事实，就能防止错误信息在无意中传播；而且，在核实的过程中，还可能获得一些有趣的新信息点滴，可以纳入自己所传播的内容之中。
Some have argued that the public is not educated enough to understand scientific information, especially for any complex phenomena, but this is absurd.
有人认为，公众受教育程度不够，理解不了科学信息，尤其是有关复杂现象的信息，但这种说法是荒谬的。
Science instruction can be found at all levels of public education, with most secondary schools offering classes on biology, physics, and chemistry.
公共教育的各个阶段都有科学教学，大多数中学都开设了生物、物理和化学课。
If anything, social media has shown that the public craves knowledge based on a solid scientific foundation.
甚至可以说，社交媒体已经表明，公众渴望获得建立在坚实科学基础之上的知识。
Even the public discourse that follows most scientific articles shows that online readers can understand even the most baffling of scientific principles.
就连大多数科学文章后面的公众讨论也表明，网上的读者甚至能理解最令人费解的科学原理。
It is equally imperative to emphasize that being an expert on a topic does not automatically make a scholar qualified to communicate it to a nonscientific audience.
同样必须强调的是，学者身为某个话题的专家，并不会因此自动具备向非科学界受众讲解这一话题的资格。
A number of scientists recently have been offering public-aimed explanations of scientific phenomena.
最近，一些科学家一直在就科学现象给出面向公众的解释。
Even though they have appropriate credentials, they often do very little in the way of explaining.
尽管具备相应的资历，他们却往往并没有真正解释清楚多少东西。
One biologist shared an intricate analogy involving a library, books, paper, a recipe, ingredients, and a cake to explain the process behind vaccines.
一位生物学家为了解释疫苗起作用的过程，分享了一个错综复杂的类比，其中涉及图书馆、书、纸、食谱、配料和蛋糕。
Any explanation that requires a written key to keep track of what each item represents is not a clear example for public consumption.
任何解释，如果需要借助一份书面对照表才能记清每一项各代表什么，就不是供公众理解的清晰例子。
Science communication is a science in and of itself.
科学传播本身就是一门科学。
It requires rigorous training and instruction.
这需要经过严格的训练和指导。
A scientist should take communication courses that can teach a person how to identify and eliminate jargon and how to develop effective analogies to explain complex concepts.
科学家应该修读传播方面的课程，这类课程能教人如何识别并剔除行话，以及如何构思有效的类比来解释复杂的概念。
One cannot assume communication expertise—imagine if someone just decided that they were a physicist and started trying to contribute to the field without the necessary background.
谁都不能想当然地认为自己具备传播方面的专业能力——试想一下，如果有人只是认定自己是物理学家，就在不具备必要背景的情况下开始尝试为这一领域作贡献，会是什么情形。
Doing a poor job communicating science to the public will only create confusion and widen the gap between science and society, a gap that scientists are trying to close.
向公众传播科学如果做得不好，只会制造困惑，拉大科学与社会之间的鸿沟，而科学家们正努力弥合这道鸿沟。